{Software developer & Web developer}

www.IamBielMir.com

OBJECTIVE

I am fortunate enough to work in programming and new technologies as they are a major passion of mine. This industry offers me different opportunities everyday and helps to grow. I'm always motivated to work hard. I'm very proud that my passion about this field has helped me be self-sufficient since a young age.

SUMMARY

Analyst and software developer. I have 7 years of industry experience, in both government-owned and private companies. Due to my formation and versatility, my strengths have been focused around the full-stack development of web administrative systems (CRUD, CMS, business process managers). I have had the opportunity to participate in the different steps of software creation - scoping, design, development, implementation, management and data management. Because of this experience, I have a wide set of skills across tools, frameworks, programming languages, and interpersonal skills.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Purple Wifi

Manchester, Uk — 2015-Now();

Working on our own cloud-based platform using PHP, Symfony 2 and Doctrine ORM, integrating a MySQL database. I get the chance to work in the Analytics team, on Developing and improving visualization methods and researching new DB engines (InfluxDb).

- My Taks: Develop and Research.
- Skills: PHP, Symfony2, Doctrine, Git, Linux, Nginx, Mysql, InfluxDb.

Lead software developer, IMAS {Government-owned corporation}

Palma de Mallorca — 2007-2015

Thanks to my technical experience and knowledge about all different areas of the company, I was involved along many steps of the creation of new software and got to work on projects with a big impact. For instance, my knowledge in the jobs involve of social services helped to design technology improving their management and, as a result, citizen services. These kind of online social services has always been under explored, so it was very interesting and rewarding to develop these custom applications.

{Software developer & Web developer}

www.IamBielMir.com

Corporate Web: A single point of access to details on all Balearic Island social services can be found. Our version of directgov / gov.uk

- My Tasks: Educate and coordinate a team for correct implementation of the project specs. Lead technical owner.
- Skills: Ubuntu, LAMP, Drupal, SQL, PHP, CSS, HML, SVN

Intranet service (about 1500 employees): Web application where employees can keep up to date on matters of their interest - career advancement, crm, meetings, etc.

- My Tasks: Project manage and communicate with business stakeholders. Lead technical owner.
- Skills: Ubuntu, LAMP, Drupal, SQL, PHP, CSS, HML, SVN

HSI, **Integrated Social History:** This application serves as a file manager, CMS, CRM for all social entities in the Balearic Islands, both governmental and private. Used by around 200 professionals from different fields including administrative assistants, social workers, psychologists, educators; and servicing more than 90,000 citizens. It won the first prize by Social Services national organisation "SOCINFO" in the Balearics.

- My Tasks: I took charge of planning, scoping, developing, management, data mining, analysis of possible improvements and formation on the use of this application. Lead technical owner.
- Skills: SQL, PHP, LAMP, Ubuntu, Jquery, Ajax, iReport, JasperServer, Mysql, Google Maps, SVN

GCM. Contracts manager: This application allows to control and manage the contracts with our service providers. Generate and archive all documentation needed for the correct transaction of the contract. Also it helps the coordination between different services which are involved.

- My Tasks: I took charge of planning, scoping, developing, management, data mining, analysis of possible improvements and formation on the use of this application. Lead technical owner.
- Skills: SQL, PHP, LAMP, Ununtu, Jquery, Ajax, iReport, JasperServer, SVN

RMI. Insertion Minimum Rent: This application manages the economical help provided to citizens that are disadvantaged or in social risk of social exclusion. Deals with the calculation of payments for over 1500 families monthly for a value of around 7 million euros. At an internal level it also helps to improve collaboration between the financial and social teams.

- My Tasks: I took charge of planning, scoping, developing, management, data mining, analysis of possible improvements and creation of the necessary documents needed to pay by transaction. Lead technical owner.
- Skills: SQL, PHP, LAMP, Ununtu, Jquery, Ajax, iReport, JasperServer, SVN

{Software developer & Web developer}

www.IamBielMir.com

Web Developer, Refineria Web

Palma de Mallorca — 2006-2007

Web Design and development, front end and back end, all in one. Web layout for all kinds of websites, adaptable to any kind of device and browser combination (Responsive Design, HTML5, css3, Jquery, SEO). Implementation of common APIs to improve the web sites and user interfaces (Google maps, Facebook, Twitter).

- My Taks: Develop and coordinate with the design team.
- Skills: HTML, CSS, Jquery, PHP, Windows

COURSES

NOW();

University of Michigan (coursera.org)

Phyton { Python,Regular Expressions,Files }

University of Colorado (coursera.org)

Beginning Game Programming with C# { C#, OOP, XNA, MonoDevel-MonoGames }

University of Maryland (coursera.org)

Mobile App for Android Handheld Systems { Java, Android SDK, Android Studio }

2013/14 - 2013/14

Ministerio de España

Web Service "Sius" - (30h) { Apache Tomcat,install Oracle, scripts }

2011/12 - 2011/12

Plan de Formación IMAS

Information security(PHP) - (35h) { Secure web architecture, SQL injection, XSS }

2009/10 - 2009/10

Plan de Formación IMAS

• Linux (33h) { Bash Scripting, Commands in Unix }

Plan de Formación IMAS

Java (33h) { J2EE, JSP, OOP }

Plan de Formación IMAS

• Java || (33h) { Web services, Advanced J2EE, OOP, Data persistence }

{Software developer & Web developer}

www.IamBielMir.com

Plan de Formación IMAS • Oracle { SQL, PL/SQL }	2008/09 - 2008/09
EDUCATION	
Sant Josep Obrer • Software architecture - Higher Education	2006/07 - 2007/08 ation (HNC)
Sant Josep Obrer	2004/05 - 2005/06
Electronic consumer equipment - High	gher Education (HNC)
Government of Balearic Islands • Certificate in "Web Design and Multi	media"
SKILLS	
	Software
Soft Davidonar	
Soft. Developer	
Web Daveloner	
Web Developer	
Web Developer Data Mining	
	Language
Data Mining English Intermediate { In constant evolution	Language and improvement. Currently taking daily academy lessons to improve my spoke education courses, both to improve my fluency and my technical skillset. }
Data Mining English Intermediate { In constant evolution	and improvement. Currently taking daily academy lessons to improve my spoke

{Software developer & Web developer}

www.IamBielMir.com

1	41	ГТ	R	Т	Ŧ	n	E.	R	T	7	T.	F	\cap) T	?]	\/	[/	۱ ک	T	Γ		1	1	Ī
- 1	٠,	L J	11.						- 1	- 1	w		N 1	יו ע	N 1	w	1 /	٦.			Α.	<i>#</i> I		4

One of my other passions is outdoor sports and competitions. All my life, I have been linked to clubs or teams of cycling or triathlon. In fact in I have been a triathlon semi-professional, being federated and competing in lots of national races.